https://www.drhallowell.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Edward M. Hallowell, M.D. is committed to responsible use of your personal information, and we recognize the importance of your privacy. Obligations and standards under this Privacy Policy apply to our staff, customers, clients, suppliers, partners, and any person working on behalf of Dr. Hallowell, LLC. regardless of whether your personal data is stored electronically, on paper, or by other methods.
Purpose
We collect personal information:
To efficiently deliver services made available on our Website.
To detect and protect against breach of contract, fraud, theft, and other illegal activity in connection with the Website.
To distribute information about services and products we offer.
Collection of Information
We collect two kinds of information: (1) personally identifiable information that you choose to provide, and (2) non-personally identifiable information. These types of information are described as follows:
Personally Identifiable Information: We collect personally identifiable information ONLY with your knowledge by your providing it upon request. This personally identifiable information may include your email address, name, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other information to enable you to make purchases, subscribe, or receive newsletters. At time of enrollment in one of our programs, very personal detailed information is requested on a voluntary basis to start service in an efficient manner. From time to time, we may request information from you via surveys or polls. Participation in these surveys or polls is completely voluntary. You have a choice whether or not to disclose the requested information. The information you provide will be used to satisfy your requests, notify you of changes to the Website or our Website policies, or provide further information about our products and services. Survey or poll information will be used for the purposes of monitoring or improving use and satisfaction of our Website and may be compiled anonymously. We will carefully handle any information you provide and will not use it in any way that you have not agreed to under this privacy policy.
Non-Personally Identifiable Information: We may collect anonymous browser information as you visit our Website. This information does not identify you personally and is not linked to any individual person. When you visit our Website, we collect this information by storing it in the form of a “cookie” on your computer. Cookies allow us to respond to your interests and preferences. With most Internet browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions to learn more about these functions.
We may also collect information through IP addresses that  include demographics. An IP address is a number used by computers on the network to identify your computer so that data can be transmitted to you. Demographics may include the domain from which you access the Internet, the time of your visit to our Website, the type of browser and operating system or platform used, the Internet address of the Websites you visited before and after visiting our site, and the pages you visit while at our site. We collect this information to allow us to detect broad trends to provide information tailored to your interests and to enhance your experience on our site. This information may be compiled in an anonymous manner.
Use of Information
We may use the information you provide to fulfill your requests for membership, newsletters, products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, and to offer you other products, programs, or services that we believe may be of interest to you. We sometimes use this information to communicate with you in instances such as fulfilling a request by you or to notify you when we make changes to our agreements or to fulfill purchase orders. The information we collect is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate your participation and from time to time to offer you products, programs, or services.
We will not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease personal information we collect. We may share personally and non-personally identifiable information with third parties that help manage our Website and databases and with our partners, affiliates, or other third parties. We may disclose personal information (1) as may be permitted or required by law or court order, (2) as may be necessary to protect our rights or property, or (3) to select third party agents with whom we have contracted to carry out internal operations of the site.
We may collect anonymous browser information and analyze our Website logs to constantly improve the value of the materials available on our site. From time to time we may link anonymous browser information with personally identifiable information to improve our site and provide you with content and offers that we think may be of interest to you.
Third parties referred to in this section may be online services such as Google Analytics, AdWords, AdSense, and others.
Information Collected
This Privacy Policy outlines how we handle your personal information to protect your privacy. We want you to know that we adhere to privacy legislation that governs what information may be collected, how it is used, and how it is protected. The terms of this policy will govern the use of any information collected while the policy is in place. We reserve the right to change this privacy policy and encourage you to revisit this page. Should we change our privacy policy, we will post such changes at this site and will attempt to notify you by email of such change. If you do not agree with these terms and conditions, you may unsubscribe and/or discontinue all use of this website.
Identifying Purposes
Personally identifiable information is information that you choose to supply. It is collected from our site by obvious request only. You have the right to decline to have any information collected or transferred for marketing purposes.
Consent
We do not knowingly collect information from or about individuals under the age of 18 unless they are specifically enrolling for services after payment and with parental consent.. Typically, we seek consent for the use or disclosure of your personal information at the time of collection. In certain circumstances, consent may be sought after the information has been collected but before usage (e.g., when we want to use information for a purpose not previously identified).
Withdrawal of Consent
You may withdraw your consent for us to collect, disclose, or otherwise use your personal information at any time subject to any legal restrictions and upon reasonable notice. Such withdrawal of consent may impact our ability to provide services to you. You may request us not to send marketing communications to you by following the opt-out instructions in each communication.
Limiting Collection
If we ask you to provide personal information, you will be asked for it specifically. The Website will not gather personal information surreptitiously. Certain information may be required so that you may receive further information. If you want us to call, we will need your name and phone number. If you want to receive email, we’ll need your email address. If you want to buy something, we’ll need your payment information and your address.
Survey participation is completely voluntary. If you choose to participate in an online survey, you may decide whether to disclose the requested information. This information will be used to monitor and improve our site and/or our products and services. Otherwise, any information you provide to us will not be used in ways that you have not agreed to by accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy.
We may supplement the personal information you provide with additional personal information gathered from public sources or from third parties, such as consumer reporting agencies and others who may lawfully provide such information to us. You are under no obligation to provide personal information. However, your refusal to do so may prevent you from using certain of our services or products.
The term “third parties” refers to partners we use for Website apps, social media, messaging systems, advertising services, and other products, services, or technologies. These third parties may collect information about apps on your various devices, the Websites you visit, and location or other information. They may share demographic information about you with their partners to improve services, for research and analysis, to provide personalized advertising, and to help them provide you with more innovative experiences and content to communicate their offers.
Information You Make Public
The Website may contain features that permit you to upload, post, transmit, display, perform, or distribute content, information, or anything else, including your personal information. Anything you choose to disclose by means of such features becomes public information over which we have no control. You should exercise caution when disclosing your personal information by means of such features, and you agree to assume all responsibility for doing so.
Testimonials are made public after we receive your specific consent.
Limiting Use, Disclosure, and Retention
We are committed to protecting your privacy as follows:
We will never give, share, sell, trade, loan, rent, or disclose any personally identifiable information about you without your express permission except as may be required by law.
We will protect every credit card transaction made from our Website.
We will promptly remove your contact information from our promotional mail and email lists upon request.
We will, however, disclose personal information specifically, but not inclusively, as may be permitted or required by law or court order or as may be necessary to protect our rights or property and to select third-party agents with whom we have contracted to carry out internal operations of the site. For example, if you want to register for an event or fulfill a purchase or delivery request, it is necessary that we pass that information along to the right party. We may also share personally and non-personally identifiable information with third parties that help manage our Website and databases.
We use secure methods and practices to store and/or transfer your personal data.
Outside our normal communication with you, your name or other personal data may be disclosed in the following circumstances:
To accrediting bodies who are tracking professional development to verify credential requirements are met and if needed to audit practice to ensure professional and ethical standards are met.
If we believe on reasonable grounds that such disclosure is necessary to avoid a significant risk of serious bodily harm to yourself or others, but we will make every effort to disclose only the minimal information necessary to avoid such harm.
If you have specifically given us your consent to disclose such information for a designated purpose.
If we are obligated by law or by court order.
Storage
When personal data is stored on paper, it will be kept in a locked drawer or cabinet, or in another secure place where unauthorized persons cannot see it.
When data is stored electronically, on servers, in cloud apps, and other means, it will be protected from unauthorized access, accidental deletion, and malicious hacking.
Even though we take reasonable steps to protect all important information and keep it secure, we do not accept liability for any willful, malicious, illegal, or destructive acts of a third party or parties who may access the data through unauthorized access by criminal activity, hacking, cyber attacks, or other means that may occur despite our best efforts.
Accuracy
From time to time, we may ask you to verify your personal information to ensure accuracy. It is important that the information we have on file is kept current and accurate. You must let us know if your personal information changes so that we can make any necessary changes to our records. Our email address and phone number are located below.
Safeguards
The security of your personal information is important to us. Through the use of appropriate technology and internal procedures, we take great care to maintain the security of your personal information and to prevent unauthorized access to it. Our employees and contractors who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access will never occur.
Email is not secure and can be lost, intercepted, or altered. If you send personally identifiable information to us by email, we will not be liable if it is lost or intercepted, altered, or misused by someone else. Users are prohibited from violating or attempting to violate the security of our Website. You are prohibited from (a) accessing data not intended for your use or logging onto a server or an account which you are not authorized to access; (b) attempting to probe, scan, or test our network system to breach its security; (c) attempting to interfere with service to any user, Webhost, or network system; and/or (d) sending unsolicited mail, including promotions or advertising of any kind.
Third-Party Links
Our site may contain links to other sites that we think might be of interest to you. We try to link only to sites that share the same high standards and respect for privacy, but we cannot be responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by any other site. Your link to another site subjects you to the privacy and security policies of that new site. You should be sure to read the privacy policies of all Websites you visit, especially when sharing personal information.
Openness
You may request to know what personal information is held about you and to question or correct any erroneous information. If you wish to have the information, send your request in writing to the address below. All written requests will be answered within a reasonable timeframe. If your request for access is limited or denied, we will notify you in writing of the reasons. At any time, you may request to be removed from our database by notifying us through any method shown below, and we will comply promptly.
Our Contact Information
You may contact us at the mailing address below or at the Website, by phone, or by email as follows:
Phone: (617) 777-5235
Email: sryandrhallowell@gmail.com
Website: https://www.drhallowell.com
Challenging Compliance
If you have concerns or wish to complain about a breach of your privacy, please contact us in writing at this address:
144 North Road, Suite 2450 • Sudbury, MA 01776 • ph 978-287-0810
Your use of our Website represents and warrants that you have read, understand, and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not, then you should leave the site at once.
Sign up for our Newsletter
Name*Email*
As Seen On
Newsletter Archive
©1994 - 2020, Dr. Edward Hallowell and the Hallowell Centers,
All rights reserved. Content may be used only with prior permission.
